# **Hairui Wang**

Full Stack Software Engineer looking to take some challenges and make a difference by creating great applications Lake Charles, Louisiana, US | +1 (337) 853-3836 | wanghairuinmg@gmail.com https://www.hairui-wang.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/Hairui-Wang

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 3 years of full stack web development experience in integrating tools and web frameworks to develop more than 5 performance, scalable and feature-rich applications. A quick, motivated and lifelong learner, a creative problem solver and enjoys working on fun, collaborative teams

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Gophr App, Inc Lake Charles, LA

Full Stack Software Engineer

Jan 2020 - Present

- Leading develop and maintain 3 microservices based backend APIs(Shipments, Users and Inventories), which have more than 70,000 lines of codes and provide all core functions to support Consumer App, Driver App, Merchant App and Dispatch dashboard as the whole e-commerce and delivery service ecosystem
- Leading implement and maintain frontend Admin dashboard for managing orders, users and inventories and dispatching drivers used by engineers, operations and customer service across 3 teams, which has more than 40,000 lines of codes and reducing 60% manually work and phone calls
- Leading design and develop School Lunch System and integrating to delivery service completed within one and a
  half month which allows parents to order lunches for students from local restaurants and being delivered and
  generating stable revenue each week
- Participated in developing placing order feature for Consumer App
- Technologies: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, GraphQL, Mocha, React.js, HTML, CSS, Next.js, React Native

# China United Network Communications Group Co., Ltd

Beijing, China

Data Scientist

Apr 2016 - Nov 2017

- Designed the Intelligent Transportation Analysis System to process and analyze real-time mobile signaling data (3 GB/min) for the Ministry of Transport of China, which first applied during national day and exhibited on CCTV news
- Developed the Population Heat Map Analysis Platform to provide SaaS application of population statistics, user tag portrait, etc. to P&G, JD, Baidu and Starbucks for their precision marketing and got average 8% improvement
- Created a tourism big data SaaS application to provide services based on mobile phone signaling and web browsing data for the Ministry of Culture and Tourism of China, which was utilized for more than 10 provinces
- Technologies: JavaScript, Java, Python, Hadoop, Storm, ArcGIS, Oracle

## **Expert Microsystems, Inc (China)**

Beijing, China

Data Scientist

Apr 2012 – Apr 2016

- Maintained and supported Prognostic and Health Management analysis and application system with Data-Driven algorithms for complex and large industrial equipment
- Designed a Real-time Diagnosis Platform including sensors for collecting data, signal processing, algorithm analysis and dynamic results display for an electromechanical system
- Provided technical supports/presentations for the sales of 4 software suites and 6 consulting projects, contributing to 30 percent of the revenue

## **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Proficient in: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, SQL | Working knowledge of: TypeScript, Python, Java Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Next.js, Bootstrap, Ant Design Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, GraphQL

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Mathematics with Computer Science Concentration, McNeese State University
Master of Engineering, Thermal Energy and Power Engineering, Beihang University
Bachelor of Engineering, Thermal Energy and Power Engineering, Tianjin University

Dec 2019

Mar 2012 Jul 2009